Guide to the New-York Historical Society Museum Department Records 1765, 1830-2018 NYHS-RG 20
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. Exhibitions, 1941-2018; 167874; 74.08 Linear feet
  - Subseries II.B. Audubon Traveling Exhibition, 1984-1996; 170792; 4.17 Linear feet
    The subseries includes the early planning documents for the exhibition and the files related to specific venues, including contractual agreements, object lists, designs, labels, shipping, publicity, insurance, funding, and other matters. Correspondence with venues that did not show the exhibition are included. Although planning for the exhibition began about 1990, the subseries also includes inquiries and other Audubon-related matter back to 1984 that was filed with the exhibition records. The subseries also includes photocopies of correspondence with American Heritage dating back to the 1960s, but this appears to be redundant of the originals in Series I. Select Collections Correspondence.
    A companion volume was also produced: John James Audubon: The Watercolors for The Birds of America, edited by Annette Blaugrund and Theodore E. Stebbins, Jr. and published by Villard Books in 1993. The subseries includes various files concerning the arrangements for the publication of this catalogue.
    - Planning Files (10 folders), 1992-1994; 170940 (Offsite-box 245, Folder 1-10)
    - Planning Files (9 folders), 1992-1994; 170941 (Offsite-box 246, Folder 1-9)
    - Planning Files (12 folders), 1990-1996; 170942 (Offsite-box 247, Folder 1-11)
    - Planning Files (23 folders), 1992-1995; 170943 (Offsite-box 248, Folder 1-23)
    - Planning Files (13 folders), 1986-1995; 170948 (Offsite-box 249, Folder 1-13)
    - Planning Files (23 folders), 1990-1994; 170949 (Offsite-box 250, Folder 1-23)
    - Planning Files (18 folders), 1984-1994; 170950 (Offsite-box 251, Folder 1-18)
      This box includes some 1980s general correspondence and 1980s exhibition material concerning the Audubon watercolors.
    - Planning Files (10 folders), 1990-1994; 170951 (Offsite-box 252, Folder 1-10)
    - Planning Files (22 folders), 1987-1994; 170952 (Offsite-box 253, Folder 1-22)
    - Planning Files (17 folders), 1991-1994; 170953 (Offsite-box 254, Folder 1-17)
      Also includes photocopies of correspondence with American Heritage from the 1960s-1980s.
    - Planning Files. Oversize, 1994; 171054 (Drawer 12A-B10, Folder 16)
      Includes two blueline drawings of gallery lay-outs, for the Museum of Fine Arts, Houston and for the Detroit Institute of Art.
    - Planning Files. Oversize, 1994; 171055 (Drawer 12A-B10, Folder 17)
      Includes the publicity poster for the exhibition at the Art Institute of Chicago.
  - Subseries II.C. Jack Rutland and Margaret Tamulonis Files, 1992-1998; 170791; 5.17 Linear feet
    The files are arranged in two sets, with Rutland's files first, followed by those of Tamulonis. Within each set, the more substantive exhibition files are presented first.
    The subseries includes files that appear to have come from Jack Rutland and Margaret Tamulonis. Rutland joined N-YHS in 1992 as Associate Registrar for Collections, later advancing to Director of Collections & Exhibitions and, in September 1996, to Director of the Museum. Tamulonis joined N-YHS in late 1993 as Collections Management Assistant, later advancing to Registrar responsibilities as Rutland advanced. Rutland and Tamulonis left N-YHS in the late 1990s. The files principally concern the planning for various exhibitions in the mid-1990s, especially Treasury of the Past (1995), 2 X Immortal: Elvis & Marilyn (1995), Scaasi: The Joy of Dressing Up (1996), and Becoming Eleanor Roosevelt: The Early New York Years (1995). The Scaasi fashion exhibition files have detailed dressing records, control records, dismantling records, and color photographs of the exhibited fashions and mannequins, in addition to the usual exhibition documentation. Rutland's files also include proposed exhibitions, general museum matters (e.g., research requests, object donation offers) and administrative files (e.g., budgets).
    - Jack Rutland Files, 170862 (Box -, Folder -)
    - Exhibition at The Equitable Gallery (6 folders), 1992-1994; 170796 (Offsite-box 255, Folder 1-6)
    - 2 X Immortal: Elvis & Marilyn (4 folders), 1993-1995; 170797 (Offsite-box 255, Folder 7-10)
      Thematic titles to this exhibition also appear in the records as Creating Fame and Fame and Glory.
    - Treasury of the Past (17 of 21 folders), 1994-1995; 170798 (Offsite-box 256, Folder 1-17)
      Includes files related to the exhibition of N-YHS collection highlights that was installed to mark the re-opening of the N-YHS galleries. "Treasures," "Treasury," and "N-YHS Treasures" are common shorthand names for the exhibition used in these and other files.
    - Treasury of the Past (4 of 21 folders), 1994-1995; 170812 (Offsite-box 257, Folder 1-4)
    - Stonewall History Project (3 folders), 1992; 170813 (Offsite-box 257, Folder 5-7)
    - Executive Mansion Exhibition, 1993; 170814 (Offsite-box 257, Folder 8)
    - New York Foundling Hospital 125th Anniversary Exhibition (Proposed), 1994; 170815 (Offsite-box 257, Folder 9)
    - Tiffany Gallery Refurbishing, 1994-1995; 170820 (Offsite-box 257, Folder 10)
    - Negro Burial Ground. Crolius Pottery (Proposed Exhibition), 1994; 170821 (Offsite-box 257, Folder 11)
    - Schedules of Exhibitions, 1994; 170822 (Offsite-box 257, Folder 12)
    - China Birds Installation, 1994-1995; 170823 (Offsite-box 257, Folder 13)
    - On the Avenue, Fifth Avenue (2 folders), [1995]; 170824 (Offsite-box 257, Folder 14-15)
    - Luman Reed Gallery. Reinstallation, 1995; 170825 (Offsite-box 257, Folder 16)
    - Siskind Portrait of Jacqueline Kennedy, 1995; 170826 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 1)
    - Zelda: By Herself (Proposed Exhibition), 1995; 170827 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 2)
    - Sigmund Freud: Conflict & Culture (Proposed Exhibition), 1995; 170828 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 3)
    - Shaker Art, Life & Belief (Proposed Exhibition), 1995; 170829 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 4)
    - Pocahontas, 1995; 170830 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 5)
    - Wharton Costumes, 1995; 170831 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 6)
    - Dexter Hall Renovation, 1995; 170832 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 7)
    - Sony. Across the Sea of Time Benefit, 1995; 170833 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 8)
    - Theater of History, 1995; 170834 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 9)
    - Bard Retrospective (Proposed Exhibition), 1995; 170835 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 10)
    - Brin Diaries, 1995; 170836 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 11)
    - World War II, 1995; 170837 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 12)
    - Maps, 1995; 170838 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 13)
    - New York Academy of Medicine (Proposed Exhibition), 1995; 170839 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 14)
    - Tenement Museum/Rabinowitz Material, 1995; 170840 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Proposed Exhibitions, 1995; 170841 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 16)
    - Mike Wallace Exhibition Write-ups, 1995; 170842 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 17)
    - New York: Then and Now: The Upper West Side (2 folders), 1995-1996; 170843 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 18-19)
    - Steeplechase Films, 1995-1996; 170844 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 20)
    - New York Stoneware, 1995-1996; 170847 (Offsite-box 258, Folder 21)
    - The Legacy of Frederick Law Olmsted. Canadian Centre for Architecture (Proposed Exhibition), 1995; 170848 (Offsite-box 259, Folder 1)
    - New York Etchings, 1996; 170849 (Offsite-box 259, Folder 2)
    - Audubon Exhibition (Taking Flight) (3 folders), 1996-1997; 170956 (Offsite-box 259, Folder 3-5)
      Includes some documents related to the Audubon traveling exhibition of the mid-1990s.
    - Exhibition Summaries & Timeline, 1993-1995; 170850 (Offsite-box 259, Folder 6)
    - Potential Exhibit with Parsons School of Design, 1995-1996; 170851 (Offsite-box 259, Folder 7)
      Includes color slides and associated inventory, presumably of proposed exhibition content.
    - Pending Exhibitions Status, 1994; 170852 (Offsite-box 259, Folder 8)
      Includes exhibition proposals.
    - The History of New York Exhibition Planning Binder, 1995-1996; 170861 (Offsite-box 259, Folder 9)
    - Budgets (5 folders), 1994-1998; 170853 (Offsite-box 260, Folder 1-5)
      Includes exhibition and general museum budgets.
    - Proposal from the Department of Visitor Services, 1996; 170854 (Offsite-box 260, Folder 6)
    - Incoming Research Requests (2 folders), 1994-1995; 170855 (Offsite-box 260, Folder 7-8)
    - Purchase or Gift Offers (3 folders), 1995; 170856 (Offsite-box 260, Folder 9-11)
    - John Rogers Sculpture Group Survey, 1993; 170857 (Offsite-box 260, Folder 12)
    - Conservation Grants (3 folders), 1994-1995; 170858 (Offsite-box 260, Folder 13-15)
    - Administrative Matters (12 folders), 1992-1995; 170859 (Offsite-box 260, Folder 16-27)
      Includes general staff memos, calendars, notes on signage and computerization, etc. Some memos concerning exhibitions are in these folders.
    - Margaret Tamulonis Files, 170863 (Box -, Folder -)
    - Scaasi: The Joy of Dressing Up (15 of 42 folders), 1996-1997; 170864 (Offsite-box 261, Folder 1-15)
    - Scaasi: The Joy of Dressing Up (15 of 42 folders), 1996-1997; 170961 (Offsite-box 262, Folder 1-15)
    - Scaasi: The Joy of Dressing Up (3 of 42 folders), 1996-1997; 170963 (Offsite-box 264, Folder 1-3)
    - Scaasi: The Joy of Dressing Up (9 of 42 folders), 1996-1997; 170962 (Offsite-box 263, Folder 1-9)
    - Scaasi: The Joy of Dressing Up. Oversize, 1996; 171053 (Drawer 12A-B10, Folder 16)
      Includes two copies of the plan, elevation, and details.
    - Metropolitan Lives: The Ashcan Artists and Their New York (4 folders), 1996; 170866 (Offsite-box 264, Folder 4-7)
    - Becoming Eleanor Roosevelt: The Early New York Years (19 folders), 1995-1996; 170865 (Offsite-box 265, Folder 1-19)
    - Staffordshire Exhibition, 1994; 170867 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 1)
    - What A Crock! New York State Stoneware, 1994-1996; 170979 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 2)
    - Clement Clarke Moore, 1995-1996; 170980 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 3)
    - Then & Now: Upper West Side, 1996; 170981 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 4)
    - Mormon Exhibition, 1997; 170982 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 5)
    - Meyerowitz, 1996; 170983 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 6)
    - Boltanski: Inventory, 1995; 170984 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 7)
    - Perspectives on New York: Selections from the Map Collection, 1995; 170985 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 8)
    - New York Celebrates the End of the War (WWII), 1995; 170986 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 9)
    - Chappaqua Library, 1996; 170987 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 10)
    - Hearts(?), Undated; 170988 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 11)
    - A Stitch in Time, Undated; 170989 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 12)
    - Arts & Antiques / 5th Ave. (Artists & Artisans of Early New York), 1996; 170990 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 13)
    - Robert Fulton, 1996; 170991 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 14)
    - Tiffany, 1995; 170992 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 15)
    - Nieuw Amsterdam, 1996; 170993 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 16)
    - Audubon, 1996-1997; 170994 (Offsite-box 266, Folder 17)
  - Subseries II.D. Kimberly Orcutt Files, 1986-2012; 170793; 2.5 Linear feet
    The subseries includes files of Kimberly Orcutt, an Associate Curator of American Art at N-YHS circa 2005-2012. Much of the material in the subseries concerns Orcutt's work for the exhibition and catalogue John Rogers: American Stories (2012). In addition to planning documents and images (many in CD and DVD digital format), the files hold Orcutt's research sources and related photocopies for Rogers. Three other exhibitions are also represented in the subseries: Life's Pleasures: The Ashcan Artists' Brush with Leisure (2006), Swing Time: Reginald Marsh and Thirties New York (2012), and Young New York (2007), an exhibition at the Park Avenue Bank Gallery. The files also hold offers of objects for purchase or donation and incoming research inquiries.
    The subseries is arranged in chronological order.
    - Offered for Gift or Purchase (2 folders), 2007-2008; 171000 (Offsite-box 267, Folder 1-2)
    - Inquiries, 2006-2011; 171001 (Offsite-box 267, Folder 3)
    - Life's Pleasures: The Ashcan Artists' Brush with Leisure, 2005-2007; 171008 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 1)
      Includes 3 CDs of uncertain content.
    - Ashcan Symposium, 2007; 171009 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 2)
    - Park Avenue Bank Gallery / Young New York, 2006-2007; 171014 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 3)
    - Swing Time: Reginald Marsh and Thirties New York (3 folders), 2010-2012; 171011 (Offsite-box 268, Folder 4-6)
      Includes 5 CDs of images and 1 CD of the NEA grant application.
    - John Rogers: American Stories (9 of 44 folders), 2006-2012; 171015 (Offsite-box 269, Folder 1-9)
      Includes color slides of John Rogers: Household Gods installation. Includes 9 DVDs of videos and images, including of the installation of the exhibition at Palmer Museum of Art.
    - John Rogers: American Stories (17 of 44 folders), 1986-circa 2010; 171016 (Offsite-box 270, Folder 1-17)
    - John Rogers: American Stories (10 of 44 folders), circa 2010; 171017 (Offsite-box 271, Folder 1-10)
      This box includes only photocopies of Rogers-related research material.
    - John Rogers: American Stories (8 of 44 folders), circa 2010; 171018 (Offsite-box 272, Folder 1-8)
- Series III. Curatorial and Administration Files, 1934-2013; 167875; 39.92 Linear feet
  Portions of the series are restricted. See the Access Restrictions note at the subseries level.
  Subseries III.A. General Files
  Subseries III.B. Museum Collections Committee Files
  Subseries III.C. Mary Black Files
  Subseries III.D. Holly Hotchner Files
  Subseries III.E. Annette Blaugrund Files
  The Curatorial and Administration Files series includes records of the museum curatorial staff, principally Mary C. Black (1970-1982), Holly Hotchner (1989-1994), and Annette Blaugrund (1989-1995). The series also holds records of the museum staff's recommendations to the Board Museum Collections Committee. In large part, the files include correspondence concerning proposed exhibitions, general exhibition scheduling, research inquiries, offers of objects for accession, object surveys, and other museum matters. Hotchner's files, especially, also include conservation and general administration matters. Although the bulk of the files date from the 1980s to 1990s, there is a set of files from as early as 1939, the point in time when N-YHS first began to expand and professionalize its museum staff. These early files include accession notes, loan records, and other museum matters.
  - Subseries III.A. General Files, 1934-1966, 1985-2001; 167889; 5.42 Linear feet
    The subseries includes various sets of general files produced by the Museum Department over time and these are presented in roughly chronological order or in the order they were accessioned into the archives. The start of each discrete set is labeled in the container list as "Set A," "Set B," and so forth. The arrangement of each set varies, as follows:
    Set A follows original order. This was alphabetical by correspondent, though some collection names, if different from the donor, were used to determine filing. Set A has a complete A-Z run that is followed by a second A-Z run. These have overlapping content and the second run simply appears to be additional related documents found at a later time.
    Set B follows original order. This was chronological, with folders of correspondence for each month. At the end of the set are folders of declined offers, arranged alphabetically by the offering correspondent or object. Regardless of the fact that these particular files were segregated in the original files, correspondence concerning declined offers can also be found in the main run of Set B.
    This subseries includes files from the Museum Department that have a mix of subject matter and that seem to have been created over time by various staff members, or perhaps by a single but no longer identifiable staff member (i.e., of mixed or uncertain provenance). Additional materials will likely accrue to the subseries over time. As of 2016, there are two "sets" of records in the subseries, designated in the container list simply as "Set A" and "Set B."
    Set A includes files that combine both registrar and curatorial matters. The bulk of these files span 1939-1949, dating from the earliest days when N-YHS expanded its museum professional staff. The principal contributors to these files appear to be Carolyn Scoon (Registrar and later Assistant Curator, ranging from the 1940s to about 1966) and H. Maxson Holloway (Curator during part of the 1940s). The date range of the files extends to the 1960s so correspondence to Director R.W.G. Vail and others do appear, in addition to Scoon. The correspondence primarily concerns offers of objects accepted and declined, inquiries regarding objects, loans to and from N-YHS for exhibitions, photograph permissions, and other object-related matters. The subseries includes extensive information about accessions in the form of correspondence, accession receipts, lists, appraisals, and acknowledgements. Library accessions are reflected in these records to a significant degree as well as those of the museum. Donors/correspondents are noted in the container list below when they are represented in a file by substantive documentation or lengthy object lists.
    Set B includes more recent (1993-2002) files of inquiries and declined accession offers.
    - Set 1, 193x-196x; 167894 (Box -, Folder -)
    - Museum/Registrar Files. A, 1939-1965; 167890 (Box 56, Folder 1)
      Includes, among others: Arkenburgh, Arnold, Andre, Agnew, Ainslie, American Museum of Natural History (loan of Catlin paintings for N-YHS's 1941 exhibition), auction receipts from Gimbel's.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. B (2 folders), 1939-1956; 167891 (Box 56, Folder 2-3)
      Includes, among others: Blake, Belknap, Bennet, Beekman, Berry, Oscar Barck (Field Exploration), Boardman, Barlow, Brainard.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. Blair, Mrs. J. Insley (2 folders), 1934-1942; 167892 (Box 56, Folder 4-5)
    - Museum/Registrar Files. C (2 folders), 1939-1949; 167893 (Box 56, Folder 6-7)
      Includes, among others: Cox, Connor, Cooper Union (loan for 1941 exhibition of textiles at N-YHS), Clement, Corell, Constant, Constantine.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. D, 1940-1960; 167895 (Box 57, Folder 1)
      Includes, among others: Dietrich, von Drehle, Dyer, Day.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. De Groot, Adelaide Milton, 1940-1947; 167896 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Museum/Registrar Files. E, 1939-1953; 167897 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Includes, among others: Erwin, Van Horne Ellis.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. F, 1939-1958; 167898 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Includes, among others: de Luze Foley, Stuyvesant Fish.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. G, 1939-1961; 167899 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      Includes, among others: Greenwood, Guernsey, Norvin Green, Richard Gosman estate, Gruver, Gilder.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. H (2 folders), 1939-1962; 167900 (Box 57, Folder 6-7)
      Includes, among others: Hand, Marian S. Hornor (loan of objects for N-YHS's 1942 St. Nicholas exhibition), Edgar C. Hyman Co., Havemeyer, Healy, Hirsch (loan of Benjamin West-related paintings by N-YHS to Allentown Art Museum), Hazen Hyde, Hudson River Line, Hanrick.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. I-J, 1939-1963; 167901 (Box 58, Folder 1)
      Includes, among others: Irwin, Jackson.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. L, 1939-1959; 167902 (Box 58, Folder 2)
      Includes, among others: Ellouise Baker Larsen, Landauer, Rita Lawrence.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. M-N (2 folders), 1939-1966; 167903 (Box 58, Folder 3-4)
      Includes, among others: Marwick, Macomber & Co. and other institutions/museums beginning with M (loan of textiles for N-YHS 1941 exhibition), Megrue, McKesson, Murphy, Newton, Catherine Mackie, Merritt, Abbie C. Miller, Mott.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. O-Q, 1939-1966; 167904 (Box 58, Folder 5)
      Includes, among others: Overton, Odell, Walter S. Poor, Prentis, F.E. Ogden (includes original photographs and descriptions of donated models of New York buildings), Beecher Ogden, O'Conor, Paltsits.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. R, 1939-1965; 167905 (Box 59, Folder 1)
      Includes, among others: Richards, Roudin, Root, Katherine Rogers, Francis Rogers, Rives.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. S-T (3 folders), 1939-1962; 167906 (Box 59, Folder 2-4)
      Includes, among others: Saint Nicholas Society, Turner, Taylor, Stahl & Sherwood (loan of objects for 1942 N-YHS New York Stage exhibition), list of silver stored in the vault at July 16, 1941, Ruth Ulmann Samuel, Sheean, Tomlinson Collection, Skillin, Schermerhorn, Sealy (Edward Wyer letterbook), Sherwood, Squier, Tinker, Tyler (Gallatin).
    - Museum/Registrar Files. U-V, 1939-1949; 167907 (Box 59, Folder 5)
      Includes, among others: Verplanck, Voorhies.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. W-Z (2 folders), 1939-1966; 167908 (Box 59, Folder 6-7)
      Includes, among others: Ziller, Zabriskie, Wheeler (Abeel kas, with original photograph), Garrett Winter, Louis C. Wills, Helen Wright, Wetherby, Whittemore.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. A, 1954-1957; 167909 (Box 60, Folder 1)
      Includes: Van Wyck Anthony, Douglas Anderson, Frederick B. Adams.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. B, 1948-1962; 167910 (Box 60, Folder 2)
      Includes, among others: Natalie K. Blair.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. Beekman, 1948-1958; 167911 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Museum/Registrar Files. Belmont, 1955-1962; 167912 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Museum/Registrar Files. C, 1935-1961; 167913 (Box 60, Folder 5)
      Includes, among others: Charles Halsey Clark, Carey, Chanler.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. D, 1950-1961; 167914 (Box 60, Folder 6)
      Includes, among others: Davis, Deavenport.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. Eberstadt, 1956; 167915 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Museum/Registrar Files. E-G, 1948-1962; 167916 (Box 60, Folder 8)
      Includes, among others: De Luze Foley, Ferguson, Stuyvesant Fish, Protestant Episcopal Church.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. Gallatin, 1951-1954; 167917 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Museum/Registrar Files. H-K, 1934-1964; 167918 (Box 60, Folder 10)
      Includes, among others: Horn, Harbord, Jay, James Foundation, Haacker, Herrick, Irwin, Keppler, Kimball.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. Hanks, 1959-1963; 167919 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Museum/Registrar Files. Hanna, 1950; 167920 (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Museum/Registrar Files. Havemeyer (3 folders), 1949-1961; 167921 (Box 60, Folder 13-15)
    - Museum/Registrar Files. Kilroe, 1948-1950; 167922 (Box 60, Folder 16)
      Includes a booklet with original bookplates and descriptions, 1905-1944.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. K, 1939-1967; 167923 (Box 61, Folder 1)
      Includes, among others: Enit Kaufman, R. Keith Kane.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. L, 1939-1961; 167924 (Box 61, Folder 2)
      Includes, among others: Landauer, Linsley.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. Livingston, 1950-1960; 167925 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Museum/Registrar Files. Lockman, 1955-1958; 167926 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Museum/Registrar Files. M-P, 1948-1961; 167927 (Box 61, Folder 5)
      Includes, among others: McKim Mead & White, Paltsits, Hudson River Day Line (A.V.S. Olcott), McKay.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. Murdock, Undated; 167928 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Museum/Registrar Files. Murphy (Prentis), 1953-1957; 167929 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Museum/Registrar Files. Quistgaard, 1951-1965; 167953 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Museum/Registrar Files. R, 1954-1961; 167954 (Box 61, Folder 9)
      Includes, among others: Rockwell, Katherine R. Rogers, Rutledge.
    - Museum/Registrar Files. Ramage, 1947; 167955 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Museum/Registrar Files. Stuart, 1944; 167956 (Box 61, Folder 11)